Finding aid for Media Resources Center (University of Michigan) Films and Videotapes, 1930s and 1948-1987
Bentley Historical Library
- Series I
  - Frontiers of Health, (Thirty-part series featuring experts from University of Michigan Medical School and Hospitals analyzes major health problems and progress in diagnosis and treatment.)
    - Rheumatic Fever, 1955-1956; [851831-I-20-15]; (Story of rheumatic fever, fourth most common cause of death among children, is told through the case of a 13 year old boy treated at UM Hospital. Features: George Lowery, UM-Med.; Richard Judge, UM-Med.)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #89, Pos. #27
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 11)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-I20-15.flv
    - Rheumatic Heart Disease, 1955-1956; [851831-I-20-16]; (A doctor and a forty year old patient discuss the symptoms, diagnosis, and treatment of rheumatic heart disease. Features: Franklin Johnston, UM-Med.; Richard Judge, UM-Med.)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #90, Pos. #28
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 11)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-I20-16.flv
    - Coronary Heart Disease, 1955-1956; [851831-I-20-17]; (Two of the most dreaded terms in medicine - angina pectoris and coronary thrombosis - are discussed as the head of the University Hospital heart station examines the causes and treatment of coronary artery disease. Features: Franklin Johnston, UM-Med.)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #91, Pos. #31
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 11)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-I20-17.flv
    - Tuberculosis I, 1955-1956; [851831-I-20-18]; (A tuberculosis specialist and his patient discuss misconceptions about the still prevalent disease. Features: Winthrop Davey, UM-Med.; Richard Judge, UM-Med.)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #92, Pos. #33
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 11)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-I20-18.flv
    - Tuberculosis II, 1955-1956; [851831-I-20-19]; (Two tuberculosis patients reminisce about their year of sanatorium life, dramatized by photographs of the University Tuberculosis Unit. Features: Winthrop Davey UM-Med.; Richard Judge, UM-Med.)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #93, Pos. #69
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 11)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-I20-19.flv
    - Artificial Limbs, 1955-1956; [851831-I-20-20]; (New developments in artificial limbs are demonstrated. Features: Sylvester O'Connor, UM-Med; Beverly Granger, UM-Med.; Richard Judge, UM-Med.)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #94, Pos. #71
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 11)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-I20-20.flv
    - Sciatica/Slipped Discs, 1955-1956; [851831-I-20-21]; (The cause and treatment of sciatica and slipped disc are discussed. Features: Carl E. Badgley, UM-Med.; Richard Judge. UM-Med.)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #95, Pos. #3554
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 11)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-I20-21.flv
    - Cataracts, 1955-1956; [851831-I-20-22]; (The treatment of cataracts is discussed, television camera will duplicate the gradual blurring of vision which develops from cataracts. Features: John Henderson, UM-Med.; Richard Judge, UM-Med.)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #96, Pos. #73
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 11)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-I20-22.flv
    - Hearing Loss, 1955-1956; [851831-I-20-23]; (Dean of the UM Medical School explains the nerve ending damage type of deafness and interviews three patients on how their deafness was overcome. Features: Albert Furstenberg, UM-Med.; Richard Judge, UM-Med.)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #97, Pos. #75
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 11)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-I20-23.flv
    - Cancer, 1955-1956; [851831-I-20-24]; (A look at how doctors work as a team in diagnosing and treating cancer. Features: Marion DeWeese, UM-Med.; Isadore Lampe, UM-Med.; James French, UM-Med.)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #98, Pos. #77
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 11)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-I20-24.flv
    - Cancer of the Lung, 1955-1956; [851831-I-20-25]; (Facts about lung cancer and smoking. Features: Herbert Sloan, UM-Med.; Richard Judge, UM-Med.)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #99, Pos. #78
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 11)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-I20-25.flv
    - Head Injuries, 1955-1956; [851831-I-20-26]; (UM neuro-surgeon discusses the symptoms of infant head injuries using anatomical drawings to illustrate internal damage that can occur, a sequence of photographs shows an actual operation to remove a blood clot from a baby's brain. Features: Richard Schneider, UM-Med.; Richard Judge, UM-Med.)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #100, Pos. #79
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 11)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-I20-26.flv
    - Aphasia, 1955-1956; [851831-I-20-27]; (Rehabilitation of aphasia victims by the UM Speech Clinic. Features: Irwin Brown, UM-Med.; Richard Judge, UM-Med.)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #101
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 11)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-I20-27.flv
    - Cleft Palate, 1955-1956; [851831-I-20-28]; (Restoration of cleft palate children by doctor, dentist, and speech therapist. Features: James Hayward, UM-Dent.; George Lowery, UM-Med.; Harlan Bloomer, UM-Med.)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #102, Pos. #88
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 11)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-I20-28.flv
    - Physical Medicine, 1955-1956; [851831-I-20-29]; (An examination of the new science of physical medicine which rehabilitates paraplegics and amputees. Features: James Rae, UM-Med.; Richard Judge, UM-Med.)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #103, Pos. #91
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 11)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-I20-29.flv
    - Appendicitis, 1995-1996; [851831-I-20-30]; (A discussion of appendicitis and lower abdominal pain in children, with films showing an appendectomy and its post-operative follow up. Features: George Lowery, UM-Med.; Marion DeWeese, UM-Med.; Richard Judge, UM-Med.)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #104, Pos. #92
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 11)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-I20-30.flv
  - Future Without Shock, (Ten part introduction to the tools and approaches of the engineer, his role and impact on society.)
    - Of Time and Consequence, 1971; [851831-I-21-1]; (This program examines the role and milieu of the engineer from ancient to modern times Features: Hansford W. Farris, UM-Eng.)
      - Original:, 2-inch video #384
    - A Delicate Balance, 1971; [851831-I-21-2]; (Concentrates on materials and man's progression from natural to synthetic materials. Features: Hansford W. Farris, UM-Eng.; George Haddad; Lawrence H. Van Vlack)
      - Original:, 2-inch video #385
    - For As Long As the Sun Shall Shine, 1971; [851831-I-21-3]; (Examines the pressures for increasing the availability of energy to emerging societies and choices we must make for our own future. Features: Hansford W. Farris, UM-Eng.; William Kerr, UM-Eng.)
      - Original:, 2-inch video #386
    - From A to D, 1971; [851831-I-21-4]; (The shift from analog-type signal transmission to digital systems, allowing for increased capacity on existing facilities. The method of dividing time is illustrated. Features: Hansford W. Farris, UM-Eng.)
      - Original:, 2-inch video #387
    - A Wondrous Complexity, 1971; [851831-I-21-5]; (Discussion of analytical tools used by the operations engineer in handling and maintaining the complex systems upon which our society depends. Features: Hansford W. Farris, UM-Eng.)
      - Original:, 2-inch video #388
    - Neither Laggard Nor Wearied, 1971; [851831-I-21-6]; (A look at the history of the computer. Features: Hansford W. Farris, UM-Eng.; Richard L. Phillips, UM-Eng.)
      - Original:, 2-inch video #389
    - The Engineering Essence, 1971; [851831-I-21-7]; (Discussion of modern engineering creativity in the field of design with David A. Sonstegard, the co-developer of the "spherocentric knee." (First Prize, International Rehabilitation Film Festival.) Features: Hansford W. Farris, UM-Eng.; David A. Sonstegard)
      - Original:, 2-inch video #390
    - The Effluents of Affluence, 1971; [851831-I-21-8]; (Examines current waste disposal methods (land fills and metal reclamation) and surveys the requirements, problems, and potential of resource recovery, also the need for disposing of unrecyclable materials. Features: Hansford W. Farris, UM-Eng.)
      - Original:, 2-inch video #391
    - Feedback, 1971; [851831-I-21-9]; (Presentation on the many ways that our society, in general, and engineering, in particular, utilize feedback processes. Features: Hansford W. Farris, UM-Eng.)
      - Original:, 2-inch video #392
    - To Be An Ingenor, 1971; [851831-I-21-10]; (A perspective on engineering suggests "Ingenor" as a title for the profession, looks at ingenuity and technological substitution as characteristics of our time, and at some of the most ingenious technological breakthroughs. Features: Hansford W. Farris, UM-Eng.)
      - Original:, 2-inch video #393
  - Genius, (One program from a series on industrial, scientific and business pioneers.)
    - Ford, 1957; [851831-I-22-3]; (Henry Ford, automotive pioneer and man of ideas, is presented and analyzed through historic film of his industry and life. Black, longtime employee and friend of Ford, discusses Ford's achievements. Includes rare footage from the Ford archives. Fred Black, UM-Eng.)
      - Original:, Pos. #808
  - Girls and Women, (Ten part series on the changing role ans status of American women.)
    - Adam's Rib, 1971; [851831-I-23-1]; (A fresh look at the nature and potential of American women. Features: Lyn Mattoon, UM-Philos.)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #105, 2-inch video #129
    - Eve's Mind, 1971; [851831-I-23-2]; (Panel explores problems and potential of four different ages and stages of womanhood. Features: Lynn Mattoon, UM-Philos.)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #106, Pos. #3454, 2-inch video #130
    - Women in the Family of Man, 1971; [851831-I-23-3]; (A variety of lifestyles are presented as alternatives to the typical white, middle-class American family structure. Features: Lynn Mattoon, UM-Philos.)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #107, Pos. #3447, 2-inch video #131
    - A Woman's Place, 1971; [851831-I-23-4]; (The position of women in ancient Rome, the Middle Ages, and the eighteenth century. Features: Lynn Mattoon, UM-Philos.)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #108, 2-inch video #132
    - New Freedoms for Women, 1971; [851831-I-23-5]; (Social changes over the past century that concern women. Features: Lynn Mattoon, UM-Philos.)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #109, 2-inch video #133
    - How the World Sees Women, 1971; [851831-I-23-6]; (Stereotypes of women presented in a dance sequence and discussed by a panel. Features: Lynn Mattoon, UM-Philos.)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #110, 2-inch video #134
    - Women, Law, and Politics, 1971; [851831-I-23-7]; (Examination of the current issues involving the freedom and rights of American women. Features: Lynn Mattoon, UM-Philos.)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #111, 2-inch video #135
    - Girls in School, 1971; [851831-I-23-8]; (Stereotypes of male-female roles presented in textbooks, teachers' fixed ideas on differences between the sexes, and the subject of counseling. Features: Lynn Mattoon, UM-Philos.)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #112, 2-inch video #136
    - What Every Woman Knows, 1971; [851831-I-23-9]; (Panel of women experienced in advising women regarding education and work responds to questions. Features: Lynn Mattoon, UM-Philos.)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #379, 2-inch video #137
    - A Woman's Work, A Woman's Life, 1971; [851831-I-23-10]; (Six women discuss their experiences in business and personal relationships. Features: Lynn Mattoon, UM-Philos.)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #113, 2-inch video #138
  - Government of Michigan, (Eight part series on state and local government in Michigan hosted by UM political scientist Daniel S. McHargue.)
    - Administrative Agencies, 1957; [851831-I-24-1]; (Eight part series on state and local government in Michigan hosted by UM political scientist Daniel S. McHargue. This program looks at state administrative agencies, what sort of powers they have, the sorts of jobs they do. Features: Daniel S. McHargue, UM-Pol.; John Lederle, UM-Pol.; Stanley Fontana, UM-SNR)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #114, Pos. #159
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 12)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-I24-1.flv
    - Finance, 1957; [851831-I-24-2]; (Where Michigan gets its money and how it goes about spending it is discussed by state Budget Director Frank Landers and Clarence Lock, Deputy Commissioner of Revenue. Features: Daniel McHargue, UM-Pol.; Clarence Lock; Frank M. Landers)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #115, Pos. #160
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 12)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-I24-2.flv
    - Civil Service, 1957; [851831-I-24-3]; (Civil Service in Michigan is discussed by C.J. Hess, state Deputy Director of Personnel. Features: Daniel McHargue, UM-Pol.; C.J. Hess)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #116, Pos. #161
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 12)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-I24-3.flv
    - The Legislature, 1957; [851831-I-24-4]; (Michigan Lt. Governor and Speaker of the House meet to discuss the law making process in Michigan -- how our state legislator works. Features: Daniel McHargue, UM-Pol.; Philip Hart; George Van Peursem)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #117, Pos. #162
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 12)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-I24-4.flv
    - The Legislator, 1957; [851831-I-24-5]; (State Representative Sallade and chain store lobbyist Doyle discuss the roles of lobbyist and legislator in the legislative process. Features: Daniel McHargue, UM-Pol.; George Sallade; Wilfred F. Doyle)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #118, Pos. #163
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 12)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-I24-5.flv
    - The Judiciary, 1957; [851831-I-24-6]; (Chief Justice of the Michigan Supreme Court and law professor discuss the court system in Michigan. Features: Daniel McHargue, UM-Pol.; Charles Joiner, UM-Law; John R. Dethmers)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #119, Pos. #164
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 12)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-I24-6.flv
    - Local Government, 1957; [851831-I-24-7]; (A discussion and evaluation of the various units of local government in Michigan. Features: Daniel McHargue, UM-Pol.; Arthur Bromage, UM-Pol.; Edward Connor)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #120, Pos. #3555
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 12)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-I24-7.flv
    - Office of the Governor, 1957; [851831-I-24-8]; (Governor Williams and two UM political scientists discuss the duties, functions and problems of the office of Governor. Features: Daniel McHargue, UM-Pol.; James K. Pollock, UM-Pol.; G. Mennen Williams)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #121, Pos. #166
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 12)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-I24-8.flv
  - Herodotus: Father of History, (Ten lectures on Herodotus and his histories by Theodore Buttrey. UM-Classics)
    - From Small Causes, 1980; [851831-I-26-1]; (Ten lectures on Herodotus and his histories. First program examines the meaning of history as Herodotus saw it in 5th century B.C. Greece, his method of interviewing people who witnessed events or knew someone who had been there. Features: Theodore Buttrey, UM-Class.)
      - Original:, 1-inch video #341
    - The Way Men Behave, 1980; [851831-I-27-2]; (Herodotus finds his role as historian, learning to give both sides of the story. Buttrey explores both myth and reality in Herodotus' Greek and Persian world. Features: Theodore Buttrey, UM-Class.)
      - Original:, 1-inch video #342
    - The Story of Croesus, 1980; [851831-I-27-3]; (How Croesus, the wealthiest man in the world, seeks immortality through continuation of blood line and reputation and then loses both. Features: Theodore Buttrey, UM-Class.)
      - Original:, 2-inch video #243
    - The Rise and Fall of Cyrus, 1980; [851831-I-27-4]; (Cyrus the Great, Persian king who conquered Cyrus and all Greek speaking residents of Asia Minor, as seen through the eyes of Herodotus. Features: Theodore Buttrey, UM-Class.)
      - Original:, 1-inch video #344
    - Curious About Customs, 1980; [851831-I-27-5]; (Herodotus was especially curious about other lands and Buttrey relates some of his best stories about the Egyptians. Features: Theodore Buttrey, UM-Class.)
      - Original:, 1-inch video #345
    - Traveler's Tales, 1980; [851831-I-27-6]; (Professor Buttrey shows Herodotus relating some of the most outlandish stories without evaluating their credibility. Features: Theodore Buttrey, UM-Class.)
      - Original:, 1-inch video #346
    - The Battle of Marathon, 1980; [851831-I-27-7]; (Looks at how the great wars began between the Persians and the Greeks. Features: Theodore Buttrey, UM-Class.)
      - Original:, 1-inch video #347
    - Folly of Xerxes, 1980; [851831-I-27-8]; (A morality tale unfolds about Xerxes, King of the Persians, trying to assume complete power over the Greeks. Features: Theodore Buttrey, UM-Class.)
      - Original:, 1-inch video #348
    - Greeks Stand at Thermopylae, 1980; [851831-I-27-9]; (Professor talks about Thermopylae and the small Spartan contingent which held off the Persian Empire. Features: Theodore Buttrey, UM-Class.)
      - Original:, 1-inch video #349
    - That These Things Shall Not Be Forgotten, 1980; [851831-I-27-10]; (The Athenian fleet destroys the Persian fleet at Salamis. Dr. Buttrey says that, for Herodotus, the facts are important, but what they tell us about human behavior is even more important. Features: Theodore Buttrey, UM-Class.)
      - Original:, 1-inch video #350
    - My Friends The Philodendrons, 1978; [851831-I-28-1]; (Twenty part series on growing and displaying plants and flowers. This program answers common questions about philodendrons. Features: Peter Kaufman, UM-Bot.)
      - Original:, 1-inch video #504
  - House Botanist, (Twenty part series on growing and displaying plants and flowers.)
    - African Violets, 1978; [851831-I-28-2]; (Propagating, fertilizing, using lights, and placing violets in the house are illustrated. Features: Peter Kaufman, UM-Bot.)
      - Original:, 1-inch video #505
    - Ferns in the Family, 1978; [851831-I-28-3]; (Discusses and displays tree ferns, Boston ferns, Staghorn ferns, and others. Features: Peter Kaufman, UM-Bot.)
      - Original:, 1-inch video #506
    - Stuck on Cactus, 1978; [851831-I-28-4]; (Examines the Christmas cactus and lesser known varieties. Features: Peter Kaufman, UM-Bot.)
      - Original:, 1-inch video #507
    - Succulents, 1978; [851831-I-28-5]; (Shows dividing, transplanting, and displaying succulents. Basic information and useful for the beginner. Features: Peter Kaufman, UM-Bot.)
      - Original:, 1-inch video #508
    - Orchid Fancier, 1978; [851831-I-28-6]; (Shows lovely and exotic orchids, also simpler varieties and beautiful wild ones. Features: Peter Kaufman, UM-Bot.)
      - Original:, 1-inch video #509
    - Begin the Begonias, 1978; [851831-I-28-7]; (Demonstrates cross-pollination and propagation from stems and leaves, and how the home gardener can have year-round begonias. Features: Peter Kaufman, UM-Bot.)
      - Original:, 1-inch video #510
    - Geranium on My Soul, 1978; [851831-I-28-8]; (Art and skill of growing America's most popular indoor/outdoor house plant. Features: Peter Kaufman, UM-Bot.)
      - Original:, 1-inch video #511
    - Potpourri, 1978; [851831-I-28-9]; (Exhibits and discusses unrelated plants (some beautiful, some exotic, some dangerous). Features: Peter Kaufman, UM-Bot.)
      - Original:, 1-inch video #512
    - Green Giants, 1978; [851831-I-28-10]; (Care of large house plants and the art of propagating from cuttings and air-layering. Features: Peter Kaufman, UM-Bot.)
      - Original:, 1-inch video #513
    - Is There a Doctor in the House, 1978; [851831-I-28-11]; (Explains pests and solutions for their removal. Features: Peter Kaufman, UM-Bot.)
      - Original:, 1-inch video #514
    - Gone for Two Weeks, 1978; [851831-I-28-12]; (Practical solutions for plant maintenance for times when plants are both unattended and attended. Features: Peter Kaufman, UM-Bot.)
      - Original:, 1-inch video #515
    - Bravo for Bonsai, 1978; [851831-I-28-13]; (Bonsai expert shows how the art of bonsai works. Features: Peter Kaufman, UM-Bot.)
      - Original:, 1-inch video #516
    - Shape Up Plants, 1978; [851831-I-28-14]; (Pruning outdoor and indoor plants. Tips on pruning for shape and health. Features: Peter Kaufman, UM-Bot.)
      - Original:, 1-inch video #517
    - Words About Herbs, 1978; [851831-I-28-15]; (Shows how to plant, maintain, and use an herb garden. Features: Peter Kaufman, UM-Bot.)
      - Original:, 1-inch video #518
    - Wild and Tasty, 1978; [851831-I-28-16]; (How to identify edible wild plants, and how to cook them. Features: Peter Kaufman, UM-Bot.)
      - Original:, 1-inch video #519
    - Beautiful But Dangerous, 1978; [851831-I-28-17]; (Poisonous plants are identified, both indoors and outdoors. Features: Peter Kaufman, UM-Bot.)
      - Original:, 1-inch video #520
    - Getting Ready for Spring, 1978; [851831-I-28-18]; (Explains seed catalogs and how to start plants indoors for later outdoor planting. Features: Peter Kaufman, UM-Bot.)
      - Original:, 1-inch video #521
    - Dyeing Can Be Fun, 1978; [851831-I-28-19]; (An expert demonstrates the art of dyeing with plants and flowers. Features: Peter Kaufman, UM-Bot.)
      - Original:, 1-inch video #522
    - The House of the House Botanist, 1978; [851831-I-28-20]; (Outdoor tour of Kaufman's own flower and vegetable gardens, and an explanation of how to make a compost heap. Features: Peter Kaufman, UM-Bot.)
      - Original:, 1-inch video #523
  - Images of America, (Fifteen part series on major ideas and events of American history.)
    - Beachhead for a Nation, 1963; [851831-I-29-1]; (This program looks at the characteristics of Puritan thinking and its contribution to the American intellectual and political heritage. Features: Charles O'Donnell, UM-Engl.; Howard Peckham, UM-Hist.)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #122, Pos. #1568, 2-inch video #129
    - Life, Liberty and Happiness, 1963; [851831-I-29-2]; (Early American growth and expansion in the seventeenth and early eighteenth centuries. Examines works of Benjamin Franklin and the Declaration of Independence. Features: Charles O'Donnell, UM-Engl.; Howard Peckham, UM-Hist.)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #123, Pos. #1569, 2-inch video #140
    - Sugar, Tea and Taxes, 1963; [851831-I-29-3]; (Looks at the events that contributed to the emergence of distinct American mind and outlook, and how the war for independence was a ramification of this. Features: Charles O'Donnell, UM-Engl.; Howard Peckham, UM-Hist.)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #124, Pos. #1508, 2-inch video #141
    - One From Many, 1963; [851831-I-29-4]; (The compromise that framed the United States Constitution and created a single nation of 13 sovereign states. Features: Charles O'Donnell, UM-Engl.; Howard Peckham, UM-Hist.; Oscar Handlin, Harvard)
      - Original:, 16mm kinescope film, neg. #125, Pos. #1509, 2-inch video #142
    - Westward to Eden, 1963; [851831-I-29-5]; (Political developments during westward expansion in the nineteenth century, and the attempts to create a national culture. Features: Charles O'Donnell, UM-Engl.; Howard Peckham, UM-Hist.; Norton Mezvinsky; Samuel Sachs)